{
    "id": "128691df151b4ab09a88feebdef54a1b",
    "title": "Simple Past vs. Present Perfect",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I .................................. read a lot of books when I was at university.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits.",
            "answers": [
                "have read",
                "used to"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2b1e3e1f50df49bea26998a004639d1f"
        },
        {
            "question": "She .................................... yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is the normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "called",
                "has called"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "29c02efed3884672a435eab1ffbe7845"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ..................................... unhappy since she left her parental home.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "13b5a4a874ca49c882aeba62418b9906"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was a child, I ……………………. with my grandparents.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "lived",
                "used to live",
                "have lived"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c647796995034aeea594bf2549f65ff3"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………. a new car yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is the normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "bought",
                "has bought"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4d08bed181104471acc128467b2824f0"
        },
        {
            "question": "The injured child ……………………….. to hospital.",
            "description": "Was taken is the passive form of took. We use the passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "took",
                "was taken",
                "has taken"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3519fe0752424f0dbb51aad2aeb0a898"
        },
        {
            "question": "Janet ………………………. her job. She is now struggling to make both ends meet.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about a finished event whose effect is still felt in the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "lost",
                "has lost",
                "had lost"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f8c9f07da1104492a464d0d4f98359e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. my arm while playing football yesterday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "broke",
                "have broken"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b86f054ce5df4d368cc1de29596c8c82"
        },
        {
            "question": "They …………………………. the dog from the pit.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "rescued",
                "have rescued",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9010843a7fc74a72bf79b3341297b38b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… from her since January.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did not hear",
                "have not heard"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8e0d11d582e34026b8335ad3cc1a78c1"
        },
        {
            "question": "Everybody …………………………. the winning team.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "congratulated",
                "has congratulated",
                "have congratulated"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "aa293ad31ffc4a6d8f45d5409c395fd5"
        },
        {
            "question": "All the students …………………………… in their work.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "handed",
                "have handed",
                "had handed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ee25458a7147413589e1654628c5758b"
        }
    ]
}